<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>engineering on Data Scientist Hiroki&#39;s Blog</title>
    <link>https://dshiroki.com/en/categories/engineering/</link>
    <description>Recent content in engineering on Data Scientist Hiroki&#39;s Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:35:46 +0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://dshiroki.com/en/categories/engineering/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>chatGPT vs Gemini: A Comparison from a Physical Model Perspective</title>
      <link>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20240304/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 16:35:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20240304/</guid>
      <description>Which Performs Better: chatGPT&amp;rsquo;s Successor Gemini? I asked both, &amp;ldquo;Which has higher performance, chatGPT or Gemini?&amp;rdquo; As of April 2023, chatGPT doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize the term &amp;ldquo;Gemini.&amp;rdquo; According to Gemini, however,
ChatGPT Strengths:  Fact-based accuracy Ethical considerations Computational efficiency  Weaknesses:  Creative writing Humorous writing Multilingual support  Gemini Strengths:  Creative writing Humorous writing Multilingual support  Weaknesses:  Fact-based accuracy Ethical issue Computational cost  As previously introduced in this blog, we wondered how the March 2024 versions of chatGPT 4 and Gemini Advanced would handle solving a physical model&amp;rsquo;s Matlab code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Mystery of Matlab&#39;s tf2ss</title>
      <link>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20240211/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 16:35:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20240211/</guid>
      <description>I love Matlab. Because it&amp;rsquo;s simple, with just the bare minimum of programming language acquisition, you can do big things easily.
And yet, it&amp;rsquo;s structured and systematic.
&amp;ldquo;You are beautiful&amp;rdquo;
Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Hiroki🐶, a data scientist.
The Mystery of the State Space Representation tf2ss from Transfer Functions as introduced in the previous blog, the handy function &amp;ldquo;tf2ss&amp;rdquo; that calculates the coefficients (A,B,C,D) of the state space representation from a transfer function is very convenient.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Relationship Between Transfer Functions and State Space Representations</title>
      <link>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20240129/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 21:15:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20240129/</guid>
      <description>Living can sometimes feel quite difficult. There are so many things that need to be done, and amidst the pressure, it&amp;rsquo;s easy to rush, make mistakes, and end up having to redo everything. &amp;ldquo;Especially when busy, don&amp;rsquo;t rush. It&amp;rsquo;s okay to do things quickly, but don&amp;rsquo;t do them in haste.&amp;rdquo; Let&amp;rsquo;s take a moment to breathe, have a cup of tea, and proceed calmly.
Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Hiroki🐶, a data scientist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State-Space Representation of Single-Degree-of-Freedom Vibration Equation(Ⅲ)</title>
      <link>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20240128/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 23:55:29 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20240128/</guid>
      <description>Single Degree of Freedom Vibrational Motion Equation Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Hiroki🐶, a data scientist.
A month has almost passed since the start of 2024. Time flies, doesn&amp;rsquo;t it? Writing this blog allows me to forget about my busy days and express my own worldview, which is an important time for me.
Now, in my previous blog, I introduced the Matlab code for solving the single degree of freedom vibrational motion equation shown in the diagram below:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State-Space Representation of Single-Degree-of-Freedom Vibration Equation(II)</title>
      <link>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20231227/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 23:50:43 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20231227/</guid>
      <description>Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Hiroki🐶, a data scientist. In my previous blog, I introduced the Matlab code to solve the single degree of freedom vibration motion equation. I have modified it a bit more to represent it in terms of inputs and outputs, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to solve it this way.
 First, this single degree of freedom vibration model. Normally, it can be written as a motion equation like this:
$$\begin{align*} m\ddot{x}+c\dot{x}+kx&amp;amp;=f \</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State-Space Representation of Single-Degree-of-Freedom Vibration Equation</title>
      <link>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20231031/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2023 21:03:29 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20231031/</guid>
      <description>Single-Degree-of-Freedom Vibration Equation Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Hiroki 🐶, a data scientist. In my previous blog I introduced the Matlab code for the physical model, which actually uses a very fancy method called state-space representation.
Today, I want to delve a little deeper into this state-space representation.
So, in this post, I will introduce:
What is state-space representation? The benefits of representing a single-degree-of-freedom vibration model in state-space representation    Firstly, this is the single-degree-of-freedom vibration model.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ChatGPT x Programming of Physical Model</title>
      <link>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20231029/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2023 17:04:46 +0900</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dshiroki.com/en/engineering/20231029/</guid>
      <description>Programming Physical Modeling with ChatGPT A must-see for a student in science! Expand your learning horizons with this super convenient way to use ChatGPT!
Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Hiroki 🐶, a data scientist.
There&amp;rsquo;s been a lot of buzz recently about ChatGPT gaining new capabilities!
For example, check out this YouTube video.
  I couldn&amp;rsquo;t wait to apply this!
For instance, a fundamental model taught in the first year of engineering studies is the single-degree-of-freedom vibration model.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
